ANDRICK **SIEGMUND**

ASSOCIATE DEVELOPER



CONTACT

Aurora, CO 248-709-9323 andrick.siegmund@gmail.com LinkedIn GitHub

SKILLS

Portfolio

Languages:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Node.js), jQuery, Java, Python SQL, NoSQL, GraphQL

Frameworks & Libraries:

React, Vite, TailwindCSS, MaterialUI, Express.js,

Software Development Tools:

Git, GitHub, Jest, Vitest, OOP RESTful APIs, External APIs

Database Management:

MySQL (Workbench), MongoDB (Compass)

Technical:

Troubleshoot, Documentation, Containerization (Docker)

EDUCATION

University of Denver

Full-Stack Web Development Boot Camp Denver, CO 08/2023

Wayne State University

Bachelor of Fine Arts Detroit, MI 05/2012

INTERESTS

Computer Science
Cross-Functional Collaboration
Scalable Systems
Best Practices
SDLC
Cloud Solutions

PROFILE

As a Web Developer with ADHD, transitioning from 11 years in the restaurant industry, my journey may be at its beginning, but my dedication to excellence in programming is firmly established. I am recognized for my positive, "Can Do" collaboration style, excellent communication, enthusiasm for problem-solving, and unwavering dedication to delivering quality work, making me a valuable asset to any team.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Conceptual Consulting / Andrick Siegmund Consulting 08/2023 - Present

- Build new sites and apps using React, Node, Express, SQL, and WordPress.
- Code Review and refactor existing sites based on the current site platform.
- Collaborate closely with clients using agile methodologies to ensure alignment with expectations.
- Learn new technologies and practices to deliver modern solutions.
- Conduct comprehensive testing of all development work to uphold Quality Assurance standards

Restaurant Professional (Bartender, Beverage Director, Floor Manager)

Multiple Establishments

1/2012 - 04/2023

- Created meaningful dining experiences through excellent customer service and adept client relationship management.
- Managed challenging interactions, defusing tensions, and cultivating a welcoming, and enjoyable atmosphere for coworkers and guests alike.

PROJECTS

Front-End Software Engineer

Deans Roundtable | 01/2024 - 02/2024

- Led WordPress UX overhaul, enhancing brand focus and product visibility.
- Implemented efficient data collection strategies, easing client operations.
- Revamped site aesthetics and advised on business strategies to boost solvency.

Full-Stack Software Engineer

AppTracker | 12/2023 - 01/2024

- Spearheaded end-to-end development of a job application tracking appusing Node.js, Vite-React, and TailwindCSS with a user-friendly interface.
- Architect and implement backend with Express, GraphQL, and MongoDB.

Full-Stack Software Engineer

AstroDash | 11/2023 - Present

- Develop and architect backend infrastructure using Express and MySQL.
- Build authorization and authentication utilizing bcrypt, js-cookie, and JWT.
- Engineered data models and navigational routes with REST API practices.